I already called Mr. Dencio.
Just ride home with us.
I'll take the tricycle home.
There are no more tricycles.
I'm sure there are a lot of tricycles
on the highway.
- I'll wait there.
- Are you sure?
It's dark there.
He said he was on his way home.
And Florence is with him.
They're together?
Why, Bro, is there a problem?
What's with the Ferells,
and you really want to protect me?
What's this, messianic complex,
or all of you can't help
but be a Prince Charming?
Do you all want to save a damsel in distress?
It's not a weakness to ask for help.
Sometimes, that's the way things are.
We need others so we can bounce back.
Sometimes, you have to be true
to what you're feeling.
Don't be scared to show it to others.
You said that we should be true to ourselves.
Well, then I'll be true too.
I know
so you don't have to look at me that way.
And besides, I know I'm not your type
especially when I saw
your ex-girlfriend Antonia.
There's a huge difference between us.
If you compare Antonia with me,
that's heaven and earth.
I'm the earth part.
That's heaven and earth.
You too, you're heaven.
Heaven, heaven, heaven...
that's you and Antonia, you're both heaven
while I'm the earth
and you really won't fall for me.
And besides, how would you fall
for your crude cook?
That's impossible.
Why would it be impossible?
You're not difficult to like.
Hello, Lina, I'm here on the third floor,
where are you?
Guys, have you seen Florence?
I know she has a class right now.
But I passed by her classroom
and she was not there.
Lina!
Congrats, you followed our instructions.
Finally, you're learning.
Is anyone there?
Kindly open the door.
Hello?
Lina!
I'm just looking for Nero.
Have you seen him?
Oh, Nero.
He's just there.
Florence!
Drink some more.
I'm okay now.
We have a clinic.
Do you want me to take you there?
I'm okay now.
Thank you for saving me earlier.
I thought I'd be locked there forever.
Are you sure they didn't
do anything else to you?
They just locked you inside the room?
Yes.
I just had a panic attack
because I'm scared of the dark.
That's really my biggest phobia
and what I hate most.
Maybe a traumatic event happened to you
when you were young.
Maybe I just get scared easily.
How did you find out where I was earlier?
Where is she?
If you won't tell me where she is...
you'll have to fight with me.
Camille and Aira won't stop bothering me.
Do you want us to report them to the dean?
No need.
So, you'll just let them?
It's not that I'll just let them be,
but I just thought Lina will be blamed
because she's the one
who called me to go there.
That's how Camille and Aira
work by deniability.
I'm sure if I'll report them,
they'll just deny it.
And in the end,
Lina will be the one reprimanded by the dean.
She might even get suspended
even if in truth,
she was just being used in this situation.
She's a victim...
A victim of Camille and Aira just like me.
But still, she let them use her.
Nero, not everyone is as brave as you.
And not everyone can make a stand easily.
If you'll let this slide now,
for sure, they'll just repeat it.
Don't worry, I'll just be careful.
Extra, extra, more.
Just forget about that.
You're really a good person, Florence.
I told you, you're not difficult to like.
I'll go to my class.
Me too.
Where are you going?
To the classroom.
You're really a good person, Florence.
I told you, you're not difficult to like.
Go to sleep, Florence.
Go to sleep.
My name is Ashley Salongga
but you can call me Ash.
And welcome to GU TV.
This is the official streaming channel
of Gyronella University.
So whoever you are, our dear hearts,
fellow family members, siblings,
chatter, or whatever you may be.
This is your go to place
for anything and everything Gyronellan.
And for our pilot episode,
we'll talk about a very important
and special day
that is unique for Gyronella University.
A day we like to call Agora Day.
But what is Agora Day?
Why is this so important for the Gyronellans?
What's this? Is this a party?
Is this the same level as Coachella?
Why does GU have something called Agora Day?
And to discuss more about that,
I invited a special someone
today with us here in the studio.
He is one of the brightest
and smartest students of our university,
and not to mention,
he will be the next leader
of our third-world country.
Please welcome to the studio,
none other than Sean Owen Ferell.
Welcome to our first broadcast, Owen.
So glad to have you here.
Well, it seems I have no choice
after you blackmailed me
to be a part of this program.
Exactly.
So, let's head on to our first question.
Are you still single?
It's just a joke. Just joking.
It's just to get the ball rolling.
But... Okay, here it is.
You are here to talk about Agora Day.
So, please tell me and our viewers
what this day is all about.
Well it's not a party, Ash.
But maybe the correct definition
is it's a celebration.
A celebration of democracy.
Wow, democracy.
Big word.
Exactly.
Because today is the day we Gyronellans
will be able to nominate
our student representatives.
Each department of the university
has the chance
to elect its student representative.
The reason why we call this Agora Day
is that we're trying to mimic
the Greek concept of Agora Market,
the earliest form of democracy.
Where the stakeholders
will gather whatever their background is
to vote for their student leaders.
So how are the elections done?
Well, it's just simple.
The student will nominate
the most popular from the department.
Starting with Economics,
Philosophy, Business Management, Marketing,
and of course, Communication Arts.
And if no one will comment or challenge them,
then he or she will automatically become
the student representative.
Oh, but what happens
if someone makes a challenge?
That has never happened in the history of GU.
All the time, students vote
for the most popular, and influential,
especially if they come
from an influential family.
So no one will bother to challenge them.
It's tiring.
I wonder where are those three fools?
Yeah, it's pretty.
I love the assorted ones.
It's so fab.
Oh, yeah. I love red as well.
Speaking of the devil.
It's a cutie... the sunflowers.
Yes, it's a cutie.
Bro.
It's weirdo, I mean, Nero.
- Sorry, it sounds alike.
- The half has a different nationality.
Where are you going?
Hello.
Hello, everybody.
Hello, Gyronellans,
and welcome to our Agora Day.
Today is a very important day
because we will be deciding
who from the student committee
will be working with me
in organizing our exciting activities.
So, are you ready
to elect our representatives?
Yeah!
Let us start with Philosophy.
We nominate Socrates,
the greatest thinker of all the universe.
You can't nominate someone who is...
well, dead.
Socrates will never die.
He will continue to live
in our hearts and minds.
His thoughts and ideas are
the foundation of our civilization.
So, he is alive
because he lives within all of us.
What about Marketing?
We nominate Lester Sumalangit.
Any objections?
Anyone who'd like to challenge
this nomination?
Alright, then that makes Lester
the head of the Marketing department.
Economics?
We nominate Margaret Reyes
for the economics department.
Any objections?
Well, then that makes Margaret
the head of the Economics department.
How about Business Management?
We nominate Tristan Mateo Ferell.
Any objections?
Any challenges?
Alright, then that makes Tristan
the head of
the Business Management department.
Finally, let's move on to Com Arts.
Who will be the head of
the Com arts Department?
We nominate Camille Cortez Villarico.
Any objections?
Anyone that would like
to challenge this nomination?
Alright, then that makes
Camille the head of the...
I object!
She objects.
I challenge her nomination...
and I nominate myself
to be the student representative
of the Communication Arts department.
That's possible, right?
I can challenge her nomination
and nominate myself.
Definitely.
We were just shocked
because this is something new.
Excuse me?
How dare you!
Well as the rules suggest,
if we have two nominees,
both will be given a chance
to convince you to choose them
as your representative.
We will reconvene to decide
who, between Camille and Florence,
will the student body choose
to be the representative
of the Communication Arts department.
This is a complete shock!
For the first time ever
in the university's history,
there are two nominees for the representative
of the Communication Arts department.
And to give us additional insight
on this historical event,
let's welcome to the studio,
Aldus Rafael Ferell.
You're right, this is new territory
for our beloved university.
And you see, we have a tradition here.
The richest student, the most influential,
and the biggest clout
is automatically elected as representative
of their respective departments.
And all the time, no one objects.
You know, when Camille topped
the dean's list last year,
everyone expected her to become
the representative of Com Arts.
And to add to that,
she's the most popular in her batch.
So she's a shoo-in already
as the departmental rep.
Tradition dictates
that she should sit
on the highest throne of Com Arts.
But for the first time in history,
someone is willing
to go against that tradition.
And for a school
that governs strong traditions,
this Florence girl is way over her head.
You may ask why?
She's a freshman.
We don't even know
what's her family background.
Well, I heard
that she's one of the beneficiaries
of our school's Scholarship Program.
That's good for her.
I heard that she cooks well...
but does she have the capabilities
to become a representative of Com Arts?
Well, either way,
we cannot independently verify the claim
that she's a good cook.
So, what will happen now?
Well, we could do what the Greeks did
before they were trivialized
by Zack Snyder in the movie "300".
I mean, anyway,
we can solve this by casting our votes.
According to the rules,
there's no unanimous decision,
and every student will be given
a chance to vote.
And each candidate, in this case,
Camille and Florence have a chance
to introduce themselves
to the whole student body.
So, what do you think, Aldus?
Who are you rooting for in this battle?
Well, it's...
I will answer that question.
The odds are definitely against Florence.
I will shave my head
if she will win over Camille.
I mean, we love David vs Goliath stories,
but David is an exemption.
Because in reality, Goliath always wins.
You can even ask the USA Dream Team
or the National Football Team of Germany.
I have nothing against you, Florence.
But the truth is,
you have no chance of winning.
Period!
What came into your mind, Florencia?
Why did you nominate yourself?
Don't tell me you're having second thoughts.
Me, having second thoughts?
Of course not. Me, of all people.
Of course not.
Yes, I don't know why I nominated myself.
I don't know what went into my mind earlier.
It's because you followed your heart.
In the short time that you're here,
you found out what kind of person Camille
and her friends are.
And you felt like you had to do something.
Your heart is telling you
that you can't let them take the position
just to terrorize others.
And even if you're not thinking about it,
you followed your heart.
But my heart is putting me in danger.
Why, did your heart ever put you in danger?
You know, with the short time I've known you,
your best quality...
is your heart.
There are a lot of intelligent
and witty people in this world.
But if there are more people like you,
this world would be so different.
It will be a whole lot better.
So don't doubt yourself.
Show everybody the power of your heart.
She has the nerve!
She's really something
to challenge me out in the open.
I hate her.
Every fiber of my being hates her.
Relax, you're overreacting.
"Relax, you're overreacting".
If she did this to you,
for sure you'll overreact too.
Don't vent your frustrations on me.
We're on the same side here.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I just really hate her.
Did I already say
that every fiber of my being hates her?
Yes, you've been saying that line
over and over.
And that's a symptom
that she's getting into you.
So just calm down because you'll still win.
I know.
I can't just believe that she has the audacity....
to challenge me out in the open.
Don't worry, you'll have a chance.
A chance for what?
A chance for us to destroy her
once and for all.
How?
Here is Michael.
What can he do?
Well, I can do anything, Camille.
I can do a new reality.
As they say, perception is real,
truth is not.
Exactly.
Michael can do anything.
He is the best graphic artist
in the university,
and he will help us create one story
that is so humiliating,
Florence will have no choice
but to quit school.
In the great tradition of disinformation.
Great job.
Florence is really a fool.
Because of her, our Agora day is extended.
You know, we should be supporting her.
I'm not saying we will not support her,
but does she have a realistic chance
against Camille?
Of course not, but it's not about winning.
At this point, you already know Florence.
It's more about making a point.
Exactly.
Do you know where Owen is?
Owen?
Maybe he's campaigning for Florence.
Among the four of us,
he's the one who supports Florence.
I told you so.
I think to some degree,
he and Florence are very much alike.
I mean, they think the same way.
They believe in something
that is difficult to believe.
You can say that again.
With what we're about to do,
that girl will stand no chance.
We will ruin her.
We will destroy her.
Let's destroy Florence.
Get rid of her irritating existence.
I know you're all excited
because today we're a new territory.
And I know that I've been hearing
that these shouldn't be happening,
that there are traditions in Agora.
However, just like any tradition,
this is subject to gradual change.
And today, we will figure out
if this tradition is good.
And at the same time,
we will decide who will be the representative
of the Com Arts department.
I now present to you, Camille and Florence.
I will destroy you.
Now is your chance, Florence,
to introduce yourself and convince them
that you deserve the position.
Thank you, Antonia.
Hello.
I'm sure you're now thinking
that I'm thick-skinned,
because I'm going against
the flow of your trend in Agora
and your tradition too.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Florence Dela Cruz.
You should not be here.
You're right.
I should not be here.
But there's nothing you can do
because I'm now here in front of you.
The truth is, I don't know why I did this...
but someone told me
that's because I'm following my heart.
So, here I am, following my heart,
and I know it's corny,
or using your term, cringe.
Even though I've been here in GU
for only a couple of days,
I can see the real you.
Oh my gosh.
- Yes.
- Girl!
- My heart sees you.
- Hurry up!
Stop limping around.
And my heart can hear you too.
That's why I can feel
what you're going through here.
Hey! Zoom in on her.
And sometimes what I can see,
hear, and feel...
can crush the heart.
Which is ironic.
Because, with our time now,
there are a lot of devices and ways
to put ourselves out there,
but it seems no one sees,
hears, or feels each one of us.
Every day we save our courage
to step out of our safe spaces
and offer ourselves to the world.
But I can sense that you are scared.
You are scared to be yourselves.
We are scared to be judged
and to commit mistakes.
That's why, here I am
standing in front of you to say
I can see, feel, and hear you all.
I understand all of you.
We all want the same thing.
We have the same fears and worries,
and we all want
to be the best versions of ourselves.
So, what I'm trying to say is...
I am here in front of you, offering myself.
I don't have much.
I don't really have much to offer.
But if you need a person to listen,
if you need someone to talk to,
to understand what you're going through,
and that the very least...
I can be that person.
And I promise, I will never judge you.
That's all.
Thank you for giving me
a chance to talk to you.
Blah, blah, blah.
That was a nice speech.
"I see you, I hear you, I feel you."
And she validates each one of you.
As if all feelings are valid.
So blah, blah, blah.
Again.
Well, let me tell you this,
how about my feelings?
Aren't my feelings valid?
I am the victim here.
Tradition dictates
that I should be the Com Arts representative.
I am the top of my class,
of our batch to be exact.
I am the one you all know.
I'm the face of my department.
Not to mention, my dad recently made it
to Forbes Magazine Billionaire's List.
That is why I should be
your Com Arts representative.
Because at the very least,
that's what is due to me.
That's what it should be.
I'm entitled to it.
But okay,
let's just assume...
let's just say
that tradition does not matter.
Let's not do anymore
what we are used to doing.
Judge us for who we are.
Game.
Do you think
she is worthy
to be your Com Arts representative?
Bea?
Michelle?
Ooh...
Next.
Camille, that's not true.
Girl, this is my time,
so please don't interrupt me.
Don't be rude.
I agree guys, she's pretty charming.
I, for a fact, wanted to be her friend too.
But yesterday, I saw her.
I saw her making a fool of herself.
That's why I took those photos
because my eyes couldn't believe it.
So, is that the representative that you want?
Someone who is so messed up.
Oh my, she might mess up something
in the student body.
So, if you guys still don't believe
that I should be the Com Arts representative,
don't let the face
of one of the most dynamic departments
of this university
be someone with questionable morals.
She doesn't deserve
to be your representative.
She doesn't even deserve
to be in this school.
That's enough.
It's impossible that you saw her yesterday...
that's why that's not true.
What makes you say that?
Because we were together yesterday.
Why are you together?
Do you even know her?
She's my girlfriend.
Oh my God!
That's why what you're saying is impossible,
because we were together yesterday.
You're kidding, right?
So, you're saying you know this woman,
and you're in a relationship?
Nero is saying that you're lying.
And now I'm the liar?
So, are you saying the Ferells are liars?
And maybe you want
to check the Forbes list that you're saying.
Check what place are we
on the list of billionaires.
And not to mention,
accusing us of lying is something
our family won't let you get away with it.
Because the Ferells are many things.
But to lie?
We can't do that.
You know, that's enough.
Let's proceed to vote.
Camille, stop!
I hate her!
Why is she doing this to me?
Why is this happening?
What are you looking at?
Ms. Villarico, can I talk to you?
Dean?
Girlfriend? I'm your girlfriend, Nero?
Since when?
I wasn't informed
and I didn't even receive a memo.
Don't you want it?
What do you mean "Don't I want it"?
To be fair, Nero has a point.
It's a privilege
to be a girlfriend of a Ferell.
Stop it.
And you too,
is it true that the Ferells never lie?
So, what do you call what Nero did earlier?
It's the truth?
I know we live in a post-truth world
but that's not a license for all of us to lie.
Well, technically, that's not a lie.
What technically are you talking about?
Technically,
you were in the mansion last night.
You were with me, Troy, Aldus, Tristan,
Grandfather Garp, Ma'am Serafica...
and Nero.
I was in the mansion last night
because I'm your cook.
Exactly, so Nero is not lying.
What are you talking about?
He told the whole school
that I'm his girlfriend.
And I'm not his girlfriend, I'm your cook.
Isn't that a lie?
Are you happy?
Yes, very happy.
Are you happy that you're Nero's girlfriend?
What's this?
Dream within a dream?
Wake up, Florence. Wake up.
Why are you hurting yourself?
You are not real.
I won't be flirting with you
because I'm a good, good, girl
in a good, good, world
and it's not good thing if you kiss me.
What do you need?
She's a good person.
Don't hurt her.
Why would I hurt Florence?
I know why you did that earlier.
You're trying to use Florence
to hurt Antonia.
First chance you get, you better cut it off.
Stop pretending like she's your girlfriend,
before someone gets hurt.
Shall we, my Chummy pie?